Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/mfathyrashad (LinkedIn) mfrashad.com (Portfolio) github.com (Portfolio) medium.com (Blog)

Top Skills

Web Development
Deep Learning
Computer Vision

Languages

Indonesian (Native or Bilingual)
English (Professional Working)
Malay (Full Professional)

Certifications

Cloud Architecture, Cloud Engineering, DevOps Essentials

Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure

Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Engineer Associate

Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Scientist Associate

Honors-Awards

Finalist Top 5 | 3 Days of Code Semi Finalist | Al and Big Data Hackathon (ABCDE)

Semi Finalist | Unblockathon 2019

Finalist | Reboot The Earth Hackathon

Top 16 Team | Robocon Malaysia 2018

Muhammad Fathy Rashad

Machine Learning Engineer & Researcher | Full Stack Developer Federal Territory of Kuala Lumpur

Summary

I'm a developer who loves to learn new things. Currently exploring various tech-related fields such as full-stack development, cyber security, game dev and machine learning. Besides coding and writing, I also do a bit of design.

At 15 years old, I skipped high school and entered university as the youngest student.

At 16, I published 2 mobile games with 2K+ total installs.

At 17, I was the youngest software engineering intern at Fave and started freelancing. I have worked with 10+ clients since then.

At 18, I started my own programming club, organized 7+ workshops, mentored students, and led several teams to competitions.

At 19, I have co-authored an ML conference paper with MIT, wrote 10 tech articles with 100k+ total views, and obtained 2 Microsoft certifications (Azure Al Engineer & Data Scientist).

Skills: Python, PyTorch, Keras, Django, Ruby on Rails, Unity, Docker, Unix, Git, AWS, GCP, React Native, React.js, Node.js, Javascript ES6, Angular, TypeScript HTML, CSS.

Experience

Medium

Technical Writer
July 2019 - Present (2 years 6 months)

Writer in Towards Data Science, InfoSec Writeups, and ViTrox Publications. I write articles about machine learning, cybersecurity, and my life experience with total of 150K+ views.

Massachusetts Institute of Technology Undergraduate Researcher October 2020 - July 2021 (10 months)

Co-authored conference paper "CreativeGAN: Editing Generative Adversarial Network for Creative Design Synthesis" with MIT DeCoDE Lab. The paper is accepted at ASME-IDETC 2021 conference.

Trained segmentation, generative, and anomaly detection network on a new dataset and integrated the networks for creative bike design synthesis.

Microsoft

Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador January 2021 - June 2021 (6 months)

Learn Student Ambassadors are a global group of campus leaders who are eager to help fellow students, create robust tech communities and develop technical and career skills for the future.

ViTrox Corporation Berhad Deep Learning R&D Intern June 2020 - December 2020 (7 months) Penang, Malaysia

- Developed anomaly detection model for defects with accuracy more than 90%
- Implemented a few-shot classification model for electrical components using metric learning with 99% accuracy
- Increased reporting efficiency by 30x by automating model performance report generation in computer vision tasks
- Ported a web application for data labeling into a desktop application
- Wrote 5+ technical articles
- Python, Django, PyTorch, Keras, JavaScript, Angular, Electron.js, Unix, Docke

Google Developers

Co-Founder & Tech Lead (Core Team), DSC UTP September 2019 - September 2020 (1 year 1 month) Perak, Malaysia

- Organized several technical workshops on app dev
- Built the main websites
- Plan and manage technical related issues in the club

UTP App Development Club (UTPADC)

Founder & President

June 2019 - June 2020 (1 year 1 month)

- Conducted Git, React Native and Flutter workshops for mobile app development.
- Led and won 2nd place at iUM Hackathon 2020 as UTP representative.
- Led and mentored members in CTF cybersecurity competition and ranked 9 out of 60+ teams.
- Wrote CTF write ups with 2k+ views.

Self Employed

Freelance Developer

September 2018 - June 2020 (1 year 10 months)

- Worked together with a web agency to develop 3 e-commerce websites.
- Developed 3 static websites using Jekyll and 4 mobile apps using React Native for businesses and individuals.
- Built a blogging website with customized CMS using Rails for a non-profit organization, ISTAID.
- Leveraged knowledge in Ruby on Rails, Docker, Jekyll, Git, WordPress, React Native, HTML, CSS

Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS Research Assistant December 2019 - February 2020 (3 months)

Malaysia

Worked in A Handheld, Self-aligned, Non-Mydriatic

Near Eye Module for Monitoring and Automatic Grading of Diabetic

Retinopathy project.

Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS Mobile Developer July 2019 - October 2019 (4 months)

Perak, Malaysia

- Developed a mobile app iOASIS for UTP library using React Native.
- Won gold and diamond award in 4th International Innovation & Design in Library & Information Science Competition (InDeLib).
- Leveraged knowledge in JavaScript ES6, Git, and React Native.

Fave

Software Engineer Intern (Backend)

May 2018 - August 2018 (4 months)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Fixed various bugs, wrote unit tests and refactored a large Rails app in Agile environment.
- Automated PDF report generation and emailing which saved 2-3 days of work monthly.
- Developed a promo code feature on rails admin dashboard that increased number of new users.
- Youngest intern at 17 years old.
- Leveraged knowledge in Ruby on Rails, Git, PostgreSQL, AWS, CircleCl, Sentry, JIRA and Agile (Kanban).

Education

Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Engineering \cdot (2017 - 2021)